<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act>
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-al/act/code/2-12-9" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-al/act/code/2-12-9" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#alabama-legislature" />
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-al" />
          <akn:FRBRnumber value="2-12-9" />
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-al/act/code/2-12-9/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-al/act/code/2-12-9/eng" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" />
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
        <akn:FRBRManifestation>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-al/act/code/2-12-9/eng@2025-12-31/akn.xml" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-al/act/code/2-12-9/eng/akn.xml" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
        </akn:FRBRManifestation>
      </akn:identification>
      <akn:references>
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="alabama-legislature" href="https://alison.legislature.state.al.us/" showAs="Alabama Legislature" />
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai/" showAs="Cosilico" />
      </akn:references>
      <akn:notes>
        <akn:note eId="note_history">
          <akn:p>(Acts 1955, 2nd Ex. Sess., No. 46, p. 152, ยง11; Acts 1961, Ex. Sess., No. 194, p. 2167, ยง5.)</akn:p>
        </akn:note>
      </akn:notes>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:title eId="title_2">
        <akn:chapter eId="title_2_chp_12">
          <akn:section eId="sec_2_12_9">
            <akn:num>2-12-9</akn:num>
            <akn:heading>Suspension from Sale and Seizure; Cost of Inspection and Grading After Suspension</akn:heading>
            <akn:intro>
              <akn:p>(a) Suspension from sale and seizure. Any eggs sold or offered for sale within this state or any eggs which are being transported for sale within this state which are in violation of any of the provisions or requirements of this chapter shall be subject to suspension from sale, seizure and condemnation in accordance with the provisions of Article 2 of Chapter 2 of this title, which article is applicable to the provisions of this chapter. Any person who moves, transports, sells or in any other manner disposes of any eggs after such eggs have been ordered suspended from sale without written authority from the Commissioner of Agriculture and Industries or his duly authorized agents or employees shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.</akn:p>
            </akn:intro>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>(b) Cost of inspection and grading when suspended from sale. Eggs which have been suspended or ordered withheld from sale as authorized under subsection (a) of this section shall not be released for sale, transportation or removal until all costs of the inspection, grading and releasing of such eggs by the Department of Agriculture and Industries shall be paid to the Department of Agriculture and Industries by the person on whose premises such eggs are suspended from sale or by the person who packed, graded and labeled for sale the eggs in cases, cartons, packages or other containers. The amount to be charged and collected for inspecting, grading and releasing eggs, as authorized in this section, together with the responsibility for payment thereof, shall be fixed by the State Board of Agriculture and Industries pursuant to rules and regulations providing for inspecting, grading and releasing eggs which have been ordered suspended or withheld from sale.</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:section>
        </akn:chapter>
      </akn:title>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>