<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act>
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-al/act/code/2-12-4" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-al/act/code/2-12-4" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#alabama-legislature" />
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-al" />
          <akn:FRBRnumber value="2-12-4" />
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-al/act/code/2-12-4/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-al/act/code/2-12-4/eng" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" />
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
        <akn:FRBRManifestation>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-al/act/code/2-12-4/eng@2025-12-31/akn.xml" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-al/act/code/2-12-4/eng/akn.xml" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
        </akn:FRBRManifestation>
      </akn:identification>
      <akn:references>
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="alabama-legislature" href="https://alison.legislature.state.al.us/" showAs="Alabama Legislature" />
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai/" showAs="Cosilico" />
      </akn:references>
      <akn:notes>
        <akn:note eId="note_history">
          <akn:p>(Acts 1955, 2nd Ex. Sess., No. 46, p. 152, §6; Acts 1961, Ex. Sess., No. 194, p. 2167, §2; Acts 1975, No. 342, p. 876, §4.)</akn:p>
        </akn:note>
      </akn:notes>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:title eId="title_2">
        <akn:chapter eId="title_2_chp_12">
          <akn:section eId="sec_2_12_4">
            <akn:num>2-12-4</akn:num>
            <akn:heading>Permits for Sale of Eggs Required; Permit Fee; Delinquency Penalty; Revocation of Permits and Appeals Therefrom</akn:heading>
            <akn:intro>
              <akn:p>Every retail dealer who sells eggs or offers eggs for sale in this state shall obtain a permit from the Commissioner of Agriculture and Industries which authorizes the sale or offering for sale of eggs and which shall be issued free of any cost or charge to the dealer. Such permit shall continue in effect for an indefinite period unless revoked as provided in this section or unless the commissioner requires all such permits previously issued terminated at the end of any fiscal year.</akn:p>
            </akn:intro>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>Wholesale egg dealers or any egg producer who shall elect to become subject to the requirements of this chapter, before such a dealer or producer sells eggs or offers eggs for sale in this state, shall apply for and obtain an annual permit to be issued by the Commissioner of Agriculture and Industries which shall expire on September 30 of each year and shall be renewable on or before October 1 of each year. The annual permit fee which shall be paid for each wholesale egg dealer permit shall be $5.00. The application therefor shall be on forms furnished by the commissioner, and the permit fee shall accompany each application, which amount shall be paid on or before October 1 of each year and deposited to the credit of the Egg Inspection Fund of the State Treasury. If the permit fee as required under this section is not paid by November 1 of each year or within 31 days from the date due, a delinquent penalty of 15 percent shall be added to the amount due. Failure or refusal to obtain the required permit and pay the fee due therefor is hereby declared to be unlawful and punishable under the penalty provisions of this chapter. The permits shall be subject to revocation by the Commissioner of Agriculture and Industries if the commissioner finds that the holder thereof is not complying with the requirements of this chapter, including rules and regulations adopted under this chapter. In such case the dealer shall be afforded an opportunity for hearing after at least 15 days’ notice. The notice shall state the time and place of the hearing and the reason for the proposed revocation. The commissioner shall prepare or cause to be prepared an official record, which shall include testimony and exhibits, but it shall not be necessary to transcribe shorthand notes unless requested for purposes of court review. The dealer shall have the right of cross-examination of witnesses who testify and shall have the right to submit rebuttal evidence. The decision in such a case shall be in writing and shall be accompanied by findings of fact and conclusions of law. The findings of fact shall consist of a concise statement of the commissioner’s conclusions upon each issue of fact contested. A copy of the decision and order, findings and conclusions shall be delivered to the dealer in person or by registered or certified mail.</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>Any dealer may appeal the commissioner’s decision or order to the circuit court of the county in which he resides or in which his principal place of business is located, by filing a complaint with the register or clerk of such court within 30 days after the service of notice of the decision. A copy of the complaint shall be served on the commissioner, in person or by registered or certified mail. The filing of the complaint shall stay enforcement of the commissioner’s decision, unless the court shall order otherwise. The commissioner shall transmit the record in the case to the court within 30 days after the service of the complaint. The review by the court shall be confined to the record. The court may affirm the decision or remand the case for further proceedings, or it may reverse or modify the decision if it was affected by an error of law or was unsupported by substantial evidence or was arbitrary or capricious.</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:section>
        </akn:chapter>
      </akn:title>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>